Guide to the Rochambeau Papers and Rochambeau Family Cartographic Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Map Collection of the Comte de Rochambeau, 1695-1792; Series V; 5.25; (13 boxes)
  - SEVEN YEARS' WAR
    - German Campaign
      - IK 204 Duchy of Brunswick. Johann Baptist Homann., n.d.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 1/2 x 25 1/2 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 724.
      - IK 203 Duchy of Brunswick, Diocese of Hildesheim and Principality of Halberstadt. Amsterdam: J. Danckerts.
        Map tab inscription: Brunswick/IK/203.
        Inscribed on map: duché de brunswick/eveché d'hildesheim/pte. d'halberstat
        Title and/or other information taken from map: DUCATUS/ BRUNSUICENSIS/EPISCOPATUS/HILDESIENSIS/PRINCIPATUS/ HALBERSTADIENSIS/Tabula/Per I. Danckerts/Amstelodami cum Privilegio.
        Notes: Colored. 20 x 25 11/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 725.
      - IK 202 Electorate of Hanover. Matthaeus Seutter., n.d.
        Map tab inscription: Hanovre et/Brunswick/carte allemande/ IK/202.
        Inscribed on map: elect. d'hanovre/d. de brunsvick [and] 5 pieces de feuils/12 pieces de ? [and] with arithmetic notations
        Title and/or other information taken from map: ELECTORA-/ TUS/HANOVERANI/cum ditionibus/et praefecturis suis/nova et accurata delin:/curata/a/MATTH. SEUTTERO,/GEOGR. CAES./AUG. VIND. [and] Tob. Conr. Lotter Sculps
        Notes: Colored. 26 x 19 9/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 726.
      - IK 166 Electorate and Palatinate of the Rhine. Paris: Nicolas de Fer., 1695
        Inscribed on map: Electorat/du Rhin du Palatinat/IK/166.
        Title and/or other information taken from map: ELECTORAT ET PALATINAT DU RHEIN/Partie de Celuy de MAYENCE/EVECHÉS DE SPIRE ET DE WORMS DUCHÉ DE DEUX PONTS/COMTÉS DE SPANHEIM DE LINANGE &c. Par N. de Fer 1695. Tirés Sur les/Memoires de Iean Christophe Hurten d'Ausbourg AParis Chez l'Auteur dans l'Isle du Palais/a la Sphere Royale avec Privil. du Roy. [and] C. Inselin Sculps.
        Notes: Colored. 16 13/16 x 21 9/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 727.
      - IK 236 Duchy of Lüneburg. Matthaeus Seutter., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/236. [and] duche/lunebourg
        Title and/or other information taken from map: DUCATUS/ LUNEBURGICUS/cum/COMITATU/DANNEBERGENSI/juxta PRAEFECTURAS suas/accurrate designatus/et mappa Geographica editus/per/ MATTH. SEUTTER SAC. CAES. MAJ./GEOGR. AUG. VIND. [and] Cu. Gratia et Privil. S.R.I. Vicariatg, in part. Rheni, Sveviae, et Juris Francon.
        Notes: Colored. 19 13/16 x 23 1/8 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 728.
      - IK 191 Diocese of Osnabrück. Amsterdam: Johannes Gigante., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/l91. [and] osnabruck
        Title and/or other information taken from map: OSNABRVGENSIS/EPISCOPATVS./Auctore Ioanne Gigante. [and] OSENBRVGGE [and] Prostant Amstelaedami apud Petrum Schenk, et Gerardum Valk. C. Privil:
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 15 5/8 x 19 1/2 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 729.
      - IK 224 Diocese of Paderborn. Carlet de La Rosière., 1760 (Box 8, Folder 331)
        Inscribed on map: IK/224. [and] eveché de paderborn/ carte excellente
        Title and/or other information taken from map: EVECHÉ/DE/ PADERBORN/Dressé sur de nouvelles/Observations et/Dedié/A MONSIEUR LE/COMTE DE BROGLIE/Lieutenant-Général des Armées du Roy/et Maréchal Générl. des Logis de/L'Armée de sa Majeste en Allemagne/Par M. Carlet de la Roziere/Capitaine de Dragons et Aide de/camp ds Mgre. le Msall. de/Broglie/ 1760.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Uncolored. 14 15/16 x 19 1/2 inches, overall. 7 1/2 x 5 inches, folded. Another copy, colored - see IK 222.
      - IK 223 Diocese of Paderborn. Matthaeus Seutter., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/223 [and] evechée De paderbon
        Title and/or other information taken from map: RECENS ET ACCURATA/DESIGNATIO/EPISCOPATUS/PADERBORNENSIS/IN SUAS DIOECESES ET PRAEFECT./EXACTE DISTINCTI/opera et sumptibus/ MATTHAEI SEUTTERI,/GEOGR. CAESAREI ET CHALCOGR./AUGUSTAE VINDEL./Cum Gratia et Privile. S. R. I. Vicariat./in partibus Rheni, Sveviae,/et Juris Franconici. [and] Tob: Con: Lotter, sc.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 21 x 23 11/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 730.
      - IK 222 Diocese of Paderborn. Carlet de La Rosière., 1760 (Box 8, Folder 332)
        Inscribed on map: IK/222 [and] EVÉCHÉ/DE/Paderbon/par/la Rosiere/a madame la comtesse de/rochambeau [and] de Ros. [and] with other notations illegibly made in light pencil
        Title and/or other information taken from map: EVECHÉ/DE/ PADERBORN/Dressé sur de nouvelles/Observations et/Dedié/A MONSIEUR LE/COMTE DE BROGLIE/Lieutenant-Général des Armées du Roy/et Maréchal Générl. des Logis de/L'Armée de sa Majeste en Allemagne/Par M. Carlet de la Roziere/ Capitainé de Dragons et Aide de/camp dc Mgre. le Msall. de/ Broglie/1760
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 15 1/4 x 19 1/2 inches overall. 6 1/2 x 5 1/4 inches folded. Another copy, uncolored - see IK 224.
      - IK 221 Dominion of Halberstadt. Amsterdam: Adolph Dingelsted., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/221. [and] eveche d halberstatt
        Title and/or other information taken from map: TABULA/ Geographica/PRINCIPATUS/HALBERSTADIENSIS,/Abbatiae/ QUEDLINGBURG,/Comitatus/WERNIGEROD,/ad statum novissimum/ revocata./per Chr. Adolph Dingelsted/ex Officina/PETRI SCHENKII/Amstelodami Vulgo de Ness.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 3/4 x 22 7/8 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 731.
      - IK 220 Diocese of Hildesheim. Nuremberg: Homann Erben., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/220 [and] eveché d hildesheim
        Title and/or other information taken from map: EPISCOPATUS/HILDESIENSIS/NEC NON VICINORUM STATUUM DELI=/ NEATIO GEOGRAPHICA./per/GERHARD. IUST. ARENHOLDUM/ Hildesiensem Iur. et Math. Stud./opera Haered./IOH. BAPTIST. HOMANNI S.C.M./Geographi Norimbergae.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 20 7/8 x 23 3/4 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 732.
      - IK 173 Diocese of Würzburg. Nuremberg: Johann Baptist Homann., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/173 [and] Eveché de virtsbourg
        Title and/or other information taken from map: DUCATUS/ FRANCIAE ORIENTALIS/seu SAC. ROM. IMPerij/PRINCIPATUS et EPISCOPATUS/HERBIPOLENSIS/Vulgo/WÜRTZBURGENSIS/cum omnibus suis Officiis et pertinentijs/Geographice exhibitus/à/IOH. BAPT. HOMANN/SAC. CAES MAJ. Geographo, et Regiae Beroline/ sis Societatis scientiarum membro/Norimbergae./Cum Privilegio Sac. Caes. Maj.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 1/2 x 22 9/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 733.
      - IK 216 The Duchy of Würtemburg. Nuremberg: Johann Baptist Homann., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/216. [and] Duché de virteenberg/2 feuille
        Title and/or other information taken from map: DUCATUS/ WURTENBERGICI/cum Locis limitaneis,/utpote maxima parte CIRCULI SUEVICI/praesertim Utroq MARCHIONATU BADN/SI et SYLVA vulgo NIGRA/Nova et post omnes exactissima Deline./ per/M.IOHANNEM ? [rest missing]/Pastorem Walddorffensem/ opera/IOH. BAPTISTAE HOMANNI/Noribergae
        Notes: Colored. 26 3/8 x 22 1/4 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 46, folder 734.
      - IK 234 Principality of Fulda. Nuremberg: Johann Baptist Homann., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/234 [and] abbeye de fulde
        Title and/or other information taken from map: S.R.I./ PRINCIPATUS/FULDENSIS/IN BUCHONIA/cum adjacentibus quibusdam/Regionibus adumbratus/â/IOH. BAPTISTA HOMANNO/ Sacrae Caesareae Majestatis Geographo/Noribergae./Cum Privilegio Sac. Caes. Majestatis.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 5/8 x 22 3/4 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folder 735.
      - IK 182 Map of Westphalia with the maneuvers of the battle of Bergen on the 13 April 1759. Frankfort: Joh. Jacob Stetter., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/182. [and] Bergen/Bataille./ Weterawie [and] Veteravie/IK 293 (?)
        Title and/or other information taken from map: CARTE DE LA WETERAVIE DRESSÉE SUR LES MEMOIRES, LES PLUS NOUVEAUX AVEC LE PLAN ET LES MANOEUVRES DELA BATAILLE DE BERGEN DONNE LE 13 AVRIL 1759. [and] ---ée [the first part of this word is illegible] par Joh. Jacob Stetter J.U.C [and] zu finden bey Phillipp Heinrich Hutter, in Franckfurt am [?]
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 1/4 x 22 inches. The bottom left portion of the map is detached, and the map as a whole is in very fragile condition. The detached section has been incorrectly marked at some time with what appears to be IK 293, or possibly 203, 213, 223, 243, 273.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folder 736.
      - IK 175 Principality of Halberstadt. Nuremberg: Homann Erben., 1750
        Inscribed on map: IK/175 [and] Charte De la principauté/ D'halberstat.
        Title and/or other information taken from map: Mappa Specialis/PRINCIPATVS/HALBERSTADIENSIS/una cum unitis cum eo terris COMITATVS/REINSTEIN et Dynastiae DERENBVRG, repraesen-/tans simul Abbatiam QVEDLINGBVRG & Comitat./ WERNIGERODE, nec non conterminum Principat./BLANCKENBVRG, Herciniam Anhaltinam et/Dynastiam SCHAVEN,/Delineato primum à G. Hier. RIESE, Architect. milit./Bo[?]ussico et Architecto provinciali Halberstadiensi,/Dem correctior reddita à Tobia Majero,/Societ. Cosmogr. sodali./Curantibus Homannianis Heredibus/Norimbergae A. MDCCL. [and] Carte de la Principauté de HALBERSTADT, y compris les pays incorpores, lavoir la Comte de REINSTEIN & la Dynastie de/ DERENBURG avec les Territoires adjacents, lesquels sont l'Abbaye de QUEDLINGBOURG & la Comté de WERNIGERODE, la/ Principauté de Blankenbourg etc. Publiée par les soins des Heritiers de Homann l'an 1750.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 1/16 x 21 1/4 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folder 737.
      - IK 174 The County of La Marche. The Abbeys of Werden, Essen, town of Dortmund. Amsterdam: Sanson.
        Inscribed on map: IK/174. [and] Comté de la Mark
        Title and/or other information taken from map: LE COMTÉ DE LA MARCK,/LES SEIGNEURIES DES ABBAYES DE WERDEN, D'ESSEN,/ ET LA VILLE IMPERIALE DE DORTMUNDT,/Dressé sur les Memoires les plus récents, Parle Sr. SANSON, Geographe Ordre. du Roy,/A AMSTERDAM/Chez/R. & J. OTTENS.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 16 11/16 x 21 5/8 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folder 738.
      - IK 209 Bad Pyrmont. Homann Erben., 1753
        Inscribed on map: IK/209. [and] cte de pirmont/Hanovre
        Title and/or other information taken from map: Die GRAFSCHAFT PYRMONT mit den um-/liegenden Hanoverischen, Braunschweig und Lippischen/auch Paderbornischen Graenzlaendern, von dem Herrn Haupt-/mann Overheide gezeichnet und herauss gegeben von/Homanischen Erben Ao. 1752. [and] La Comté de PYRMONT avec les Environs et les Confins des Pais/d'Hanovre, de Brounsvic, de Paderborn, et de la Com-/té de Lippe, levée sur les Lieux par Mr. le Capit. Over-/heide, et publiée par les Heritiers de Homann l'An 1752./corrigée par l'Auteur l'an 1753.
        Notes: Colored. 18 5/8 x 22 7/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folder 739.
      - IK 198 Waldenburg. Nuremberg: Homann Erben., 1732
        Inscribed on map: IK/198. [and] principaute de valdeck [and] Waldeciae
        Title and/or other information taken from map: WALDECCIAE/ ac/Finitimorum Dominiorum/ITTERANI & CANSTEINIANI/nec non insertae Dioecesis/EIMELRODENSIS/accurata Tabula, excusa/ Per/HOMANNIANOS HEREDES/Noribergae MDCCXXXIII.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 25 1/8 x 21 7/8 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folder 740.
      - IK 192 Diocese of Osnabrück. Paris: Le Rouge., 1757
        Map tab inscription: Osnabruck/IK/192.
        Inscribed on map: osnabrug
        Title and/or other information taken from map: EVECHÉ D'OSNABRUC a Paris chez le Rouge Rue des grands Augustins. 1757.
        Notes: Uncolored. 27 9/16 x 21 3/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folder 741.
      - IK 206 Electorate of Hanover., n.d.
        These maps were originally sewn together in booklet form.
        Inscribed on back of Map (possibly part 4): IK/206 [and] Hanovre. [and] électorat d'hanovre en 8 feuilles
        No title on maps
        Notes: All uncolored. 12 1/2 x 18 1/4 inches, average.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folders 742-749.
      - IK 208 Hanover. Paris: Le Rouge., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/208. [and] Hanovre. [and] hanovre.
        Title and/or other information taken from map: ELECTORAT D'HANOVER a Paris chez le Rouge Rue des Augustins.
        Notes: Colored. 31 1/8 x 22 1/2 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 863.
      - IK 193 Westphalia. Nuremberg: Homann Erben., 1756
        Inscribed on map: IK/193. [and] Cercle de Westphalie/avec les grands Chemins
        Title and/or other information taken from map: LE CERCLE DE/WESTPHALIE/DIVISÉE/en tous ses Etats/et Principautés./ DRESSÉE/Sur les Cartes des/Heritiers d'Homann/à Nuremberg./ 1756.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 22 3/4 x 18 11/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folder 750.
      - IK 186 Duchy of Westphalia. Matthaeus Seutter., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/186. [and] Duché de vestphalie
        Title and/or other information taken from map: DUCATUS/ WESTPHALIA/novâ mappâ Geographicâ/curatissime repraesentata/et secundum/DYNASTIAS/et/PRAEFECTURAS/ diligentissime distincta,/opera et fumtibus/MATTHAEI SEUTTERI,/SAC. CAES. MAJ. GEOGR./AUGUSTAE VINDEL.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 20 11/16 x 24 7/8 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folder 751.
      - IK 195 Part of the Duchy of Westphalia., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 333)
        Inscribed on map: IK/195. [and] langraviat de hesse/en six feuilles/partie du duche de westphalie
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 14 15/16 x 20 1/2 inches.
      - IK 228 From Fulde to Marburg., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/228 [and] Allemagne [and] Hesse en 6 feuilles/partie de fulde a marburg
        Title and/or other information taken from map: TERRAE PRINCIPAT. HASSO-DARMSTADINI sitae inter Fluvios Lahn et Fulda Folium IV.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 17 3/8 x 20 5/16, inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 47, folder 752.
      - IK 228bis Part of the Course of the Lahn, Ochemberg, Dillemburg and Siegen. (Box 8, Folder 334)
        Inscribed on map: IK 228bis [and] hesse en 6 feuilles/ partie du cours de la lahn, ochembourg/dillembourg et siegen.
        Title and/or other information taken from map: TERRAE PRINCIPATVS HASSO-DARMSTATTINI, ubi confines sunt Terris Principatus Nassoviensis, Siegen, Dillenburg, Dietz. Folium III.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 17 3/8 x 20 5/16 inches.
      - IK 226 Southern Hesse. Mainz: Carlet de La Rosière., 1760 (Box 8, Folder 335)
        Inscribed on map: IK/226 [and] carte de la hesse excellante/partie meridionnale [and] 2e carte a madame la/ comtesse de rochambeau
        Title and/or other information taken from map: PARTIE MÉRIDIONALE/DU LANGRAVIAT DE/HESSE-CASSEL/avec une Partie de la Vetteravie/DÉDIÉE A MONSEIGNEUR LE/MARÉCHAL DUC DE BROGLIE/Prince du St. Empire, Chevalier des Ordres/du Roy, Gouverneur des Ville et Chateau/de Bethune, Et Commandant l'Armée de/Sa Majesté en Allemagne/Par M. Carlet de la Roziere/Capitaine de Dragons Et Son/Aide de Camp./1760. Gravée à Mayence par Henry Contgers Graveur.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 20 11/16 x 33 7/8 inches overall. 7 x 5 inches, folded.
      - IK 227 Upper Hesse. Homann Erben., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/227. [and] Hesse superieure
        Title and/or other information taken from map: HASSIAE SVPERIORIS ET WETTERAV. PARTIS DELINEATIO, CVM DESCRIPTIONE CASTRORVM PROPE GIESSAM ET CONIVNCTIONIS AD/VRBAM TRAVNICI ET BATIANICI EXERCITVVM, SERENISSIMO PRINCIPI ac DOMINO, DNo. LVDOVICO, HASSIAE LANDGRAVIO, PRINCIPI/HERSFELDIAE, etc. etc. etc. humillime oblata a CHRISTOPH MAX. PRONNER, Excudentibus Homannianis Heredibus. Ao. 1746. C. P. S. C. M.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 18 3/4 x 22 1/2 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 48, folder 753.
      - IK 197 Hesse-Kassel., 1759 (Box 8, Folder 336-337)
        Two copies of the same map. Originally stored in a patterned board sleeve. See also: Oversize Sleeve Boxes, box 51.
        1) Half topographical map of Hesse - Kassel Landgraviate by Carlet de la Rossierè, drawn for intelligence use for the campaign of Soubise (1758): "1e. Cartes à Madame la Comtesse de Rochambeau"
        Map tab inscription: Hesse-Cassel
        Inscribed on map: Allemagne/Hesse Cassel [and] 1e. cartes a madame la/comtesse de rochambeau [and] cassel [and] IK/197. [and] Carte de Hesse/partie septentrionl/& M. Roziere
        Title and/or other information taken from map 1: CARTE DEMI-TOPO-GRAPHIQUE/DE LA PARTIE SEPTENTRIONALE DU/ LANDGRAVIAT/DE HESSE-CASSEL,/Avec une Partie du Duché de Brunswick,/de la Thuringe &c./Dressée pour servir à l'Intelligence de la prochaine Campagne,/et à celle de Mr. le Marechal Prince de Soubise l'an 1758./Par Mr. Carlet de la Rosiere,/Capitaine de Dragons, et Aide de Camp de Mr. le Duc de Broglie,/Lieutenant Général des Armées du Roy./ Assujettie aux Observations Astronomiques de Mrs. de l'Academie/Royale des Sciences, par le Chevalier de Beaurain, Géographe/Ordinaire du Roy, et cy devant de l'Education de/Monseigneur le Dauphin./DEDIÉE ET PRESENTÉE AU ROY,/Par le même./...Avec Privilege/du Roy./1759.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 1/4 x 33 inches overall. 6 1/2 x 4 3/4 inches, folded.
        2) Map of Hesse, excellent, Northern part.
        Inscribed on map 2: Carte/de la hesse excellente partie/ septentrionale
        Title and/or other information taken from map 2: Same as for map 1
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 19 3/8 x 33 7/16 inches overall. 6 1/2 x 4 3/4 inches folded.
      - IK 229 Map of a Part of the Present Theater of War in Germany. Mainz: Carlet de La Rosière., n.d. (Box 9, Folder 338-341)
        Inscribed on map: IK/229. [and] 1. Allemagne/ Carte de la hesse Seconde feuille/de Monsieur de la Rosiere./A Monsieur le Comte de Rochambeau
        1) Notes to map, part 1: This is the top left quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Uncolored, 28 x 28 9/16 inches, overall. 7 3/8 x 7 1/4 inches, folded.
        2) Inscribed on map: 2 Allemagne/Carte de hesse 1ere feuille de Mr./de la rosiere a Mr. le comte de/Rochambeau [and] 2e edition [and] Mr. le Cte. de Rochambeau [and] 22.e [on map proper]
        Title and/or other information taken from map, part 2: CARTE/D'UNE PARTIE DU THEATRE DE LA GUERRE PRÉSENTE/EN ALLEMAGNE, QUI COMPREND/LE LANDGRAVIAT DE HESSE-CASSEL/LE COMTE DE WALDECK, UNE PARTIE DU DUCHÉ DE WESTPHALIE, L'EVECHÉ/DE PADERBORN, UNE PARTIE DE L'ELECTORAT D'HANNOVRE ET DE LA THURINGE,/L'ABBAIE DE FULD, LE COMTÉ D'HANAU, AVEC UNE GRANDE PARTIE DE LA WETTERAVIE./DÉDIÉE A MONSEIGNEUR LE MARÉCHAL DUC DE BROGLIE/Prince du St. Empire, Chevalier des Ordres du Roy/Gouverneur des Ville et Château de Bethune, Commandant/en Chéf de la Haute et Basse Alsace et de l'Armée de Sa/Majesté Sur le Haut Rhin./Par M. Carlet de la Ro[z]iere/Capitaine de Dragons et Aide Maréchal Généra[l] des Logis de l'Armée 1761. Gravée à Mayence par Henry Contgen Graveur
        Notes to map, part 2: This is the top right quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Uncolored. 27 15/16 x 27 1/2 inches, overall. 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches, folded.
        3) Inscribed on map, part 3: 3. Allemagne/Carte de hesse. 3eme feuilles/de la Rosiere. [and] Mr. Le Cte. de Rochambeau
        Notes to map, part 3: This is the bottom right quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Uncolored. 27 11/16 x 27 5/8 inches, overall. 7 x 7 inches, folded.
        4) Inscribed on map, part 4: 4./Allemagne/Carte de Hesse/de la Rosiere [and] carte de hesse/4eme feuille
        Notes to map, part 4: This is the bottom left quarter of the map. Linen-backed. Uncolored. 27 13/16 x 28 1/4 inches, overall. 7 1/8 x 7 1/8 inches, folded.
      - IK 168 Plan of Kassel. Strasbourg., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/168. [and] Siege de Cassell [and] près Mayence
        Title and/or other information taken from map: Plan de Cassel/et de Ses attaques./M: Le Comte de Broglie/ Lieutenant général, Gouverneur/de cette place en a ordonné/ la deffence, dont les travaux/ont été dirigés par M. de Caux de/Blacquetot Ingenieur en chef./La Tranchée fut ouverte/devant cette place, la nuit/du 1er. au 2. mars 1761/ par M. le Cte. de la/Lippe Buckbourg qui/en a levé le siege/le 28. du même mois/La Couleur rouge/indique les travaux/de l'Attaque, et la/Jaune, ceux de la/deffence gravé par Striedbeck a Strasbourg.
        Notes: Colored. 24 3/8 x 30 5/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Broadside Case, folder 864.
      - IK 180 Franconia. Nuremberg: Johann Baptist Homann., n.d.
        Map tab inscription: Franconie
        Inscribed on map: IK/180 [and] Franconie ?
        Title and/or other information taken from map: CIRCULI/ FRANCONIAE/PARS ORIENTALIS ET POTIOR/novissime delineata/ quam/Illustrissimis Generosissimis ac Excellentissimis/DnDn Totig CIRC. FRANCON. LEGATIS/pro Salute publ. Norimbergae congregatis/Dominis suis Gratiosis/humillimé/D.D.D/IO. BAPT. HOMANN/NORIEMBERGAE/cum Priv. Sac. Caes. ut & Reg./ Maj. Pol.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 23 x 19 5/8 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 48, folder 754.
      - IK 196 Electorate of Mainz. Johann Baptist Homann., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/196 [and] Electorat de mayence/2me partie de franconie
        Title and/or other information taken from map: ELECTORATUS/MOGUNTINUS/ut et/PALATIN:INFER HASSIAE, &/ Fluminis Moeni aliqua pars/exhibens simul/Occid: Circ: Franconiae partes nimiru/infimam part. Episc. Würtz: Comit. Werth:/Reineck, Hohenl: & Erpach etc./Geogr. exhibitus./conante IOH. BAPT. HOMANNO S.C.M. Geog./Cum Priv: Caes:
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 22 5/16 x 19 5/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 48, folder 755.
      - IK 181 Franconia. Matthaeus Seutter., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/181. [and] Allemagne/franconie
        Title and/or other information taken from map: CIRCULUS/ FRANCONICUS,/in quo continentur/EPISCOPAT. WÜRTZBURGENS. BAMBERGENSIS,/ET AICHSTADIENSIS,/STATUS EQUITUM TEUTONICORUM./DUCAT. COBURGENSIS, MARCHIONAT. CULMBAC. BARUTH./ET ONOLDINUS, PRINCIPATUS SCHWARZENBERG./COMITAT. HENNEBERG, WERTHEIM, HOLACH, REINECK,/PAPPENHEIM, ERPACH, HANAU, CASTELL./BARONATUS SENSHEIM, TERRITOR. NORIBERGENSE,/accurate delineatus/per/MATTHAEUM SEUTTER SAC.CAES. MAJ. GEOGR. AUG. V.
        Notes: Colored. 22 x 25 3/4 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 48, folder 756.
      - IK 190 Episcopality of Münster and Osnabrück. Matthaeus Seutter.
        Inscribed on map: IK/190. [and] evechés/de munster et osnabruck [and] Vesel
        Title and/or other information taken from map: EPISCOPATUUM/MONASTERIENSIS/ET/OSNABRUGENSIS/UT ET/ COMITATUUM/BENTHEIM, TECLENBURG,/STENFORD, LINGEN, DIEPHOLT,/DELMENHORST, RIETBERG/etc. etc./novissima et accuratissima Designatio/Cura et sumptibus/MATTHAEI SEUTTERI,/S.C. ET. REG. CATHOL. MAJEST. GEOGR./AUGUSTAE VINDEL Cum Gratia et Privil. S.R.I. Vicariatus, in partibus Rheni Sveviae, et Juris Franconici. Tob. Con. Lotter, sculp.
        Notes: Linen-backed. Colored. 24 1/8 x 20 3/16 inches.
        SEE: Oversize Boxes, box 48, folder 757.
      - IK 213 Forest of Hartz. Nuremberg: Homann Erben., n.d.
        Inscribed on map: IK/213. [and] foret d'hartz [and] forêt du Hartz/Hanovre.
        Title and/or other information taken from map: Delineatio aureae Sterilitatis/Herciniensis, i.e./HERCINIAE/ METALLIFERAE/accurata Chorographia,/omnes simul fodinas & loca nativa/minerarum, quae ibi effodiuntur,/addita nomenclatura, distincte exhibens./Edita curis/Homannianorum Heredum/Norimbergae.
        Notes: Colored. 22 3/16 x 25 7/8 inches.